If someone took everything you live for... how far would you go to get it back?
Flightplan is a thriller, drama, mystery film directed by Robert Schwentke.
Flying at 40,000 feet in a state-of-the art aircraft that she helped design,
Kyle Pratt's 6-year-old daughter Julia vanishes without a trace.
Or did she?
No one on the plane believes Julia was ever onboard.
And now Kyle, desperate and alone, can only count on her own
wits to unravel the mystery and save her daughter.
Kyle, played by Jodie Foster.
Carson, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
Fiona, played by Erika Christensen.
Stephanie, played by Kate Beahan.
Therapist, played by Greta Scacchi.
Estella, played by Judith Scott.
Flightplan is a 2005 mystery psychological thriller film directed by
Robert Schwentke from a screenplay written by Peter A.
Dowling and Billy Ray.
It stars Jodie Foster as Kyle Pratt, a recently widowed American aircraft engineer living in
Berlin, who flies back to the United States with her daughter and her husband's body.
She loses her daughter during the flight and must struggle to
find her while proving her sanity at the same time.
It also features Peter Sarsgaard, Erika Christensen, Kate Beahan, Greta
Scacchi, Sean Bean, and Matt Bomer in his film debut.
Distributed by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution and released theatrically on September 23, 2005 in the United States and on October 20, 2005 in Germany, the film received mixed
reviews from critics, who praised the direction, performances of the cast (particularly Foster's), and the thriller elements of the film but criticized the screenplay.
It was also a major commercial success, grossing over $223 million worldwide against a $55 million budget, and received
two nominations at the 32nd Saturn Awards; Best Action or Adventure Film, and Best Actress (for Foster).
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, airplane,
loss of loved one, baby-snatching, flight.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.